Now that you've had some time to learn a little bit
我们已经花了很多时间学习理论
more about this and maybe try some on your own,
现在该亲手试试了
let's try running our own demo to see if we can get
现在让我们运行示例程序
fetched to work with our Web API example.
看看是否可以使用 fetch 访问 Web API
So as reminder, here we've set up the parts to our URL and then,
这里设置好了 URL 的各个部分
I've just added a simple event listener here called Click is the event listener,
然后注册了一个 click 事件监听器
Perform Action is the callback.
并且传入回调函数 performAction
So that when I click this Go button,
当点击 Go 按钮时
it will perform this action and the action that I want to do is
就会执行回调函数 在回掉函数里
I want to call the Get Animal demo function which is right here.
又调用了 getAnimalDemo 函数
You can see that our Get Animal Demo is
可以看到 getAnimalDemo 是一个
an async function that takes three parameters which are the base URL,
异步函数 它有三个参数 分别是基准 URL
the animal we want and the API key.
动物名称和 API 密钥
Then, rebuild our URL into a fetch call.
然后组合成请求 URL 传入 fetch 函数
So here we have fetch and you can imagine this,
在这里调用 fetch
because of its parts is actually a URL that would be something like Http,
传入的 URL 形如 http
animal equals tiger and then this long string and in total,
animal=tiger 然后是这一长串字符
that is what will let you query a web API.
这样就可以访问 Web API 了
So let's try to run this.
试着运行一下
Then I'll go through a little more and explain the anatomy of the async function.
然后我会深入讲解异步函数
Now I'm going to get a little tricky,
这里有点小机关
because if you remember,
你还记得吗
we made up this Web API.
这个 Web API 不是真的
So keep in mind that this is how everything would work except to really get data back,
除了返回真实的数据 其他功能都和正常的 Web API 一样
I'm going to do this.
这里我会访问一个
I'm going to fetch an API endpoint that I've set up called Fake Animal Data.
叫做 fakeAnimalData 的 API 端点
If we look here in our server file,
看一下服务器代码
we have our dummy API endpoint data right here which is fake data and we're going to
我们将数据直接保存在变量 fakeData 中
send back to our API request a lion and a fact which are lions are fun.
然后返回
This object right here actually
这个 JavaScript 对象
simulates what you're likely to get back from a real API call,
模拟了调用真实 API 返回的数据
so it's helpful to us.
用在我们的示例代码中足够了
So here we have a get route setup that says "Get Fake Animal Data" with
这里设置了 GET 路由 /fakeAnimalData
a callback function and the callback function just sends back our fake data.
并传入一个回调函数 该函数返回了模拟数据
This really does simulate how it would be to work with an API.
访问真实的 Web API 和这个在道理上是一样的
So let's test it out now.
让我们试一下
Okay. This is an interesting mistake perhaps.
嗯 貌似出了点问题
But if you see right now I still am just running a synchronous demo which I'm going
原因是我现在运行的还是同步版本的示例
to turn off and I'm going to turn on our fetched demo.
注释掉它 打开 fetch 示例
There it is. We press Go and we get back,
这下好了 点击 Go 按钮得到
So that's an example of how you would make a get request using fetch to a Web API.
这就是一个使用 fetch 访问 Web API 的例子
Now let's dive a little further into the anatomy here of what we're doing.
现在我们来深入探讨一下
So when we're calling this function Get Animal Demo,
当调用 getAnimalDemo 时
the first thing is we make it an async function by
第一件事是在函数定义前加关键字 async
adding the async keyword before the function itself.
把它变成异步函数
This gives us access to the async keywords such as await, try and catch.
这样我们就可以使用 await、try 和 catch
These come together to make a really elegant syntax for working with web APIs.
用它们访问 Web APIs 非常方便
So once we're into the meat of our function,
在函数内部
we set a variable to hold the fetch calls
我们定义一个变量存储 fetch 回来的结果
return and the await keyword is what makes this all work because
这里 await 是重点
await is telling the script not to go on to
它让代码在拿到数据后
the next part until it's received the data that it needs,
再执行下一步
because our fetch call is calling to a Web API.
由于 fetch 访问的是 Web API.
So in order for us to do something with that,
在拿它做点什么之前
we need to first get it back.
必须先等它返回
That's what await allows inside of an async function.
这就是 await 的作用
You can only use the keyword await if you've already
你只能在异步函数内部
set it up to be an async function using the async keyword.
使用 await 关键字
Once you've set up what your condition is,
条件设置好后
you want to await for the fetch call,
就等待 fetch 返回吧
then you do a try and a catch.
然后执行 try catch
A try is what happens if everything goes well.
如果不出什么错 会执行 try 里面的语句
So assuming everything goes well and we get our data back,
假设一切顺利 拿到了我们请求的数据
we want to get a new data that is in JSON format, right?
我们希望以 JSON 的形式处理数据
So this.JSON is a method that's just giving us
那么就可以调用 .json
our data in JSON which is how we want it and for now,
将数据转换为我们想要的格式
we're just going to console.log that data because it's magic as is.
我们在这里将数据打印出来见证奇迹
Next, we'll learn how we can chain events
接下来我们会学习如何链接事件
so that we can do something else with that data.
使用数据干更多的事
The catch error is keyword syntax that you can
你可以使用 catch(error)
use to make sure that if something goes wrong,
在出现异常时
you have some idea of it.
做些善后处理
Let's see what it would look like if we purposefully caused an error.
我们故意抛出个异常试试
Error. Data is not defined.
Error Data is not defined
That is a beautiful and easy way to catch errors.
这真是一个优秀的异常处理方式
So if we set our code again to work,
让我们把代码恢复原状
let's run it one more time.
再运行一次
There we go. We see we have a working get requests in an async function.
啊哈 我们又可以在异步函数中发送 GET 请求了